Guide to the Ulysses Kay papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II: Music by Kay, 1939-1991
  - Two Impromptus for Piano, 1986
    - Full score, undated (Box 28, Folder 16)
    - Full score, undated (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - String Triptych, 1987
    - Preliminary sketches and first full sketch, 1987 (Box 35, Folder 12)
      (pages of second movement--numbered by Kay as "5" and "6"--function as pages 5 and 6 of final full sketch)
    - Final full sketch, 1987 (Box 39, Folder 13)
      (pages of second movement from first full sketch function as pages 5 and 6 of final full sketch; see Kay's note on final full sketch page 4)
    - Full score, undated (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - Full score, undated (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - Alma Mater, 1987
    (arrangement of song by John Corigliano, with text by Ruth Ann Lief)
    - Text, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - John Corigliano's original setting, 1987 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Sketch of vocal parts, 1987 (Box 35, Folder 15)
      (includes sketch for an impromptu)
    - Sketch of orchestral arrangement, 1987 (Box 35, Folder 16)
    - Holograph vocal score, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Copies of vocal score, 1987 (2 items) (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Copies of vocal score, 1987 (2 items) (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Holograph of full score, 1987 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Everett Suite, 1988
    - Sketch, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - A Farewell, undated
    (circa 1941-1945)
    - Full score, undated (Box 35, Folder 17)
  - Out of the Depths, undated
    - Holograph, undated (Box 35, Folder 18)
      (unsigned)
  - Requiem, undated
    - Holograph, undated (Box 35, Folder 19)
    - Full scores, undated (2 items) (Box 35, Folder 20)
  - Scherzo for Violin and Orchestra, undated
    (circa 1944-1948)
    - Holograph, circa 1952 (Box 35, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous Sketches, 1945-1989
    - Small notebooks of sketches, 1945-1968, (6 Folders) (Box 3, Folder 63 to 68)
    - Sketches and notes for "S. G. H.", circa 1950 (Box 35, Folder 22)
    - Sketch of "Pastorale", circa 1952-1953 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Untitled sketch, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Sketch of "Theme for organ var.", 1958 (Box 35, Folder 23)
      (includes page with title "Organ Suite No. 2")
    - Sketches for "Rondo Fantasie" for accordion, 1962 (Box 35, Folder 24)
    - Excerpts from Umbrian Scene and Essay on Death, 1963-1964 (Box 35, Folder 25)
    - Sketch for "Three pieces for Flute, Oboe, and Clarinet", 1964 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Sketch of "e[?] theme", 1964 (Box 35, Folder 26)
    - Untitled sketch, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Sketches for "The Owl and the Pussy Cat" and "Calico Pie", 1965 (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Excerpt from Structures Sonores by Henri Lazarof, 1967 (Box 35, Folder 27)
    - Sketches for "Piano Sonata",1970 (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - Sketches for "Children's Pieces", 1970 (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - Sketches for "Partita II" for violin and piano, 1971 (Box 35, Folder 28)
    - Sketch for "Toccata", 1971 (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - Sketch for untitled work for piano, circa 1971 (Box 35, Folder 29)
      (includes notes regarding Ginastera's first piano concerto)
    - Sketches for "Piano Concerto", 1974 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - Sketch of "Brian's Music (Nocturne)", 1979 (Box 3, Folder 77)
      (found with sketches for Frederick Douglass, 1985)
    - Sketches using 12-tone row, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - Sketches for untitled work, 1985-1987 (Box 35, Folder 30)
      (includes page of notes)
    - Sketch for "Brevard Suite", 1989 (Box 35, Folder 31)
    - Sketch for untitled work, 1990 (Box 35, Folder 32)
    - Sketch for untitled work for brass instruments, undated (Box 35, Folder 33)
    - Sketch for untitled work for clarinet septet with additional clarinet soloist, undated (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Sketches for "Venetian Games," "Concerto for Orchestra", and "Symphony", undated (Box 35, Folder 34)
    - Pages from unidentified holograph, undated (Box 35, Folder 35)
    - Miscellaneous sketches, undated (Box 35, Folder 36)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, circa 1951-1977
    - Assorted texts, circa 1945-1972 (Box 4, Folder 51)
      (includes texts for: Song of Jeremiah (1945-1947), A Wreath for Waits (1954), Phoebus, Arise (1958-1959), Flowers in the Valley (1961), Choral Triptych (1962), Triptych on Texts of Blake (1962), Inscriptions from Whitman (1963), Two Dunbar Lyrics (1965), Four Hymn-Anthems (1965), Stephen Crane Set (1967), and Pentagraph (1970-1972); some contain markings)
    - Notes regarding "Scherzo", 1951 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Lists of composed works and projected works, 1964-1966 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Notes regarding "Symphony No. 2", 1967 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - List of duos for flutes, circa 1976 (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - Notes regarding Rochberg's violin concerto, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Texts by Francis Thompson, undated (Box 3, Folder 81)
      (page titled "Fantasies")
    - Outline of "Suite for 4 Trombones", undated (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - Miscellaneous notes, circa 1965-1972 (Box 4, Folder 55)
- Series III: Performance Programs, 1938-1994
  This series contains concert and recital programs kept by Kay. This series is further divided into two subseries: the first includes programs that feature works by Kay and the second contains programs for performances in which no work by Kay was performed. Both subseries are arranged chronologically by year of performance.
  - Subseries III.1: Programs featuring Kay, 1938-1994
    - Programs, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Programs, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Programs, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Programs, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Programs, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Programs, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Programs, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Programs, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Programs, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Programs, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Programs, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Programs, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 66a)
    - Programs, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 67)
      (Includes program from University of Michigan with a signed note from Langston Hughes.)
    - Programs, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - Programs, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 68a)
    - Programs, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - Programs, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 69a)
    - Programs, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 69b)
    - Programs, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 69c)
    - Programs, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 69d)
    - Programs, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 69e)
    - Programs, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - Programs, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - Programs, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 72)
    - Programs, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 73)
    - Programs, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 74)
    - Programs, 1971, (2 Folders) (Box 79, Folder 1a-1b)
    - Programs, 1972 (Box 79, Folder 1c)
      (Stokowski Tribute programs accompanied by correspondence and photographs)
    - Programs, 1973 (Box 79, Folder 1d)
      (includes program signed by Valentine Stein)
    - Programs, 1974, (2 Folders) (Box 79, Folder 2a-2b)
      (The first folder includes correspondence with Denis M. de Coteau)
    - Programs, 1975 (Box 79, Folder 3)
      (includes correspondence with Clarissa W. Cumbo)
    - Programs, 1976, (2 Folders) (Box 79, Folder 4 to 5)
    - Programs, 1977 (Box 79, Folder 6)
    - Programs, 1978 (Box 79, Folder 7)
    - Programs, 1979 (Box 79, Folder 8)
      (Black Arts Festival program contains correspondence)
    - Programs, 1980 (Box 79, Folder 9)
    - Programs, 1981 (Box 79, Folder 10)
    - Programs, 1982 (Box 79, Folder 11)
    - Programs, 1983 (Box 79, Folder 12)
    - Programs, 1984, (2 Folders) (Box 79, Folder 13 to 14)
      (Holland Community Chorale program in Folder 14 contains correspondence and other related documents)
    - Programs, 1985 (Box 79, Folder 15)
    - Programs, 1986 (Box 79, Folder 16)
      (Program for recital by Herman D. Taylor signed by the artist)
    - Programs, 1987 (Box 80, Folder 1)
    - Programs, 1988 (Box 80, Folder 2)
    - Programs, 1989 (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - Programs, 1990 (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - Programs, 1991 (Box 80, Folder 5)
    - Programs, 1992 (Box 80, Folder 6)
    - Programs, 1994-1996 (Box 80, Folder 7)
    - Programs, undated (Box 80, Folder 8)
  - Subseries III.2: Programs Featuring Others, 1946-1989
    These are programs that do not feature any works by Kay.
    - Programs, 1946 (Box 80, Folder 9)
    - Programs, 1947 (Box 80, Folder 10)
    - Programs, 1950 (Box 80, Folder 11)
    - Programs, 1952 (Box 80, Folder 12)
    - Programs, 1953 (Box 80, Folder 13)
    - Programs, 1966-1969 (Box 80, Folder 14)
    - Programs, 1971 (Box 80, Folder 15)
    - Programs, 1973 (Box 80, Folder 16)
    - Programs, 1974 (Box 80, Folder 17)
    - Programs, 1975 (Box 80, Folder 18)
    - Programs, 1977 (Box 80, Folder 19)
      (Lincoln Center program contains article that mentions Kay)
    - Programs, 1978-1979 (Box 80, Folder 20)
    - Programs, 1981-1982 (Box 80, Folder 21)
      (Includes a tribute for Carl Haverlin written by Ulysses Kay.)
    - Programs, 1983 (Box 80, Folder 22)
    - Programs, 1985 (Box 80, Folder 23)
    - Programs, 1988 (Box 80, Folder 24)
    - Programs, 1989 (Box 80, Folder 25)
    - Programs, 1991-1994 (Box 80, Folder 26)
- Series IV: Biographical Materials, 1940s-1995
  This series contains materials that include biographical information on Kay. These materials document Kay’s awards, catalogs of works, citations, commissions, honors, and professional activities. The series also includes biographical articles on Kay, condolence letters, curriculum vitae and résumés, obituaries, publishers’ brochures, naval service records, school transcripts, and vital records.
  - Awards and Commissions, 1982, 1992 (Box 82, Folder 5)
    (Includes a handwritten list from 1982)
  - Biographical Clippings and Articles, 1957-1972 (Box 82, Folder 6)
  - Brochures
    (These are publishers’ brochures which include biographical statements and information on Kay’s published works. Most of these were printed by BMI.)
    - Brochures, 1956-1987 (Box 82, Folder 7)
    - Brochures and Related Biographical Statements and Drafts, 1940s-1970s (Box 82, Folder 8)
  - Citation and Award Certificates, 1976-1980s (Box 103)
  - Condolence Letters on Kay's Death, 1995 (4 Folders) (Box 83, Folder 1 to 4)
  - Curriculum Vitae and Résumés
    - Summary of Training and Experience, 1940s (Box 83, Folder 5)
    - Biography and Curriculum Vita, 1980s (Box 83, Folder 6)
    - Curriculum Vitae, circa 1957-1986 (Box 83, Folder 7)
      (Includes biographical statements, lists of works, résumés, etc.)
    - Vita and Data Summary, 1968-1988 (Box 83, Folder 8)
    - Activities, circa 1968-1974 (Box 84, Folder 1)
      (Includes formal report for Leham College, lists of performances for "Markings,", and photographs)
  - Honorary Degrees, 1969, 1977-1978 (Box 84, Folder 2)
  - Honors, 1969-1993 (Box 84, Folder 3)
  - Job Offers, 1969-1989 (Box 84, Folder 4)
  - Naval Service Records, 1942-1946 (Box 84, Folder 5)
  - Navy Band Reunion Flyer, 1961 (Box 84, Folder 6)
    (This is an invitation for the band to come to the Kays’ home)
  - Obituaries, 1995 (Box 84, Folder 7)
  - Reference Material, 1966 circa 1989-1990 (Box 84, Folder 8)
    (This includes some material on Kay, as well as additional material on BMI, etc.)
  - For Scrapbook, 1949-1954 (Box 84, Folder 9)
    (Primarily clippings on Kay and relatives)
  - Transcripts, 1960s (Box 84, Folder 10)
    (Includes Kay’s transcripts and 1965 correspondence on his teaching activities)
  - University of Rochester Diploma, 1940 (Box 103)
  - Vital Records (Ulysses and Barbara Kay) (Box 84, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous, 1934, 1957-1992 (2 Folders) (Box 84, Folder 12 to 13)
    (Includes biographical information and information on Kay’s activities and catalog of works)
- Series V: Correspondence, 1941-1995
  This series consists of both professional and personal correspondence.
  - Subseries V.1: General Correspondence, 1953-1995
    This subseries consists of several files of miscellaneous correspondence that have been kept in Kay’s original file groupings.
    - 1953-1993 (3 Folders) (Box 84, Folder 14 to 16)
    - 1964-1968, 1987-1995, Undated (5 Folders) (Box 85, Folder 1 to 5)
  - Subseries V.2 Family Correspondence, circa 1944-1994
    This subseries includes correspondence from Kay’s mother, siblings, wife, and daughters. There is one file of Kay’s outgoing correspondence filed at the end of the subseries.
    - General Family Correspondence, 1961-1970, 1990 (Box 85, Folder 6)
      (Primarily from Kay’s wife and daughters)
    - Pictures, circa 1944-1973 (Box 85, Folder 7)
      (Includes photographs)
    - Jackson, Camille, 1964-1965, 1993 (Box 85, Folder 8)
    - Kay, Barbara, 1961 July (Box 85, Folder 9)
      (Two pieces of correspondence written by Barbara from prison in Mississippi, where she had participated in the Mississippi Freedom Rides. One of these includes a covering letter from a family friend)
    - Kay, Elizabeth, 1959-1970 (Box 86, Folder 1)
      (Includes two condolence letters in relation to her death in 1970.
    - Kay, Hillary, 1978 (Box 86, Folder 2)
    - Kay, Melinda, 1975-1979, 1992 (Box 86, Folder 3)
    - Kay, Virginia ("Jenny"), 1963, 1978-1979, 1994 (Box 86, Folder 4)
    - Skinner, Lillian, 1965 (Box 86, Folder 5)
    - Watkins, Bill
      - General, 1970-1971 (Box 86, Folder 6)
      - On Elizabeth Kay Trust, 1979-1991 (Box 86, Folder 7)
    - Kay, Ulysses--Outgoing Correspondence, 1965 January (Box 86, Folder 8)
      (One letter to Camille Jackson and one to Bill Watkins)
  - Subseries V.3: Personal Correspondence, 1953-1980, 1991-1994
    This subseries consists of general personal correspondence, as well as correspondence from poet Theodore (Ted) Melnechuk and composer George Rochberg.
    - General Personal Correspondence, 1958-1961, 1991-1992, undated (3 Folders) (Box 86, Folder 9 to 11)
    - Christmas Cards, 1972 (Box 86, Folder 12)
    - Melnechuk, Theodore
      - General, 1994 (Box 86, Folder 13)
      - Poem "To Ulysses Kay" with Photograph by Leo Smit taken near the American Academy in Rome, 1980 January (Box 103)
        (Originally framed and signed for presentation to Kay)
      - Poetry, 1959, 1964-1965 (Box 86, Folder 14)
    - Rochberg, George, 1953-1966 (Box 86, Folder 15)
  - Subseries V.4: Professional Correspondence, 1941-1994
    The majority of Kay’s professional correspondence was kept in the subject files which are filed in Series VI. This subseries consists of more general professional correspondence.
    - General Professional Correspondence
      - A-Z, 1941-1964, 1977 (Box 86, Folder 16 to 17)
        (Originally an alphabetized accordion file. The file includes biographical and resume data that was sent out professionally.)
      - General Correspondence, 1948-1994, undated (13 Folders) (Box 87, Folder 1 to 13)
    - Autograph Requests, 1971-1981 (Box 87, Folder 14)
    - Choral People, 1961-1980 (Box 87, Folder 15)
    - Conductors
      - Band, 1971-1979 (Box 88, Folder 1)
      - Current, 1970-1984 (Box 88, Folder 2)
      - Old, 1954-1971 (Box 88, Folder 3)
      - Promotion, 1966-1982 (Box 88, Folder 4)
    - Conductors and Managers, 1971-1974 (Box 88, Folder 5)
    - Critics’ Questions, 1969-1979 (Box 88, Folder 6)
    - Doctoral Candidates and Others, 1967-1978, 1988 (Box 88, Folder 7)
    - Drichta, Clarenace, 1986-1988 (Box 88, Folder 8)
    - Edwin Fleischer Music Collection, Free Library of Philadelphia, 1941-1976 (2 Folders) (Box 88, Folder 9 to 10)
    - Performers--Other, 1970-1983 (Box 88, Folder 11)
    - Printer in Italy, Correspondence from, 1952 (Box 88, Folder 12)
    - Producers, 1947-1948, 1963-1968 (Box 88, Folder 13)
    - Recommendations, 1969-1989 (2 Folders) (Box 88, Folder 14 to 15)
    - University Correspondence, 1971-1989 (Box 88, Folder 16)
      (Correspondence with persons at other universities)
    - Kay, Ulysses--Outgoing Correspondence, 1974-1991, undated (Box 88, Folder 17)
- Series VI: Professional Subject Files, 1941-1997
  This series contains subject files that document Kay’s professional activities. Kay’s filing system was not exact; materials related to a particular subject (such as a particular work) may be found not only in the file for the specific subject but also in the files for related persons and general subjects. The files include correspondence, announcements, brochures, clippings, contracts, notes, photographs, publicity materials, reviews, and royalty statements.
  - Address Books (2), undated (Box 89, Folder 1)
  - American Academy and Institute of Arts and Letters, 1979-1993 (2 Folders) (Box 89, Folder 2 to 3)
    (Includes photograph)
  - American Composers Concert (Russia) Poster, 1958 October 15 (Box Mapcase 15-B-4)
    (With Roy Harris and Gennady Rozdesventsky (Gennadii Rozdesventskii) conducting, featuring works by Kay and others. In Russian.)
  - American Academy in Rome, 1968-1980, 1933 (Box 89, Folder 4)
  - American Music Center, 1977-1978 (Box 89, Folder 5)
    (Includes Kay’s curriculum vita)
  - Analysis, 1970-1971, undated (Box 89, Folder 6)
    (Analysis of several pieces of music, some annotated)
  - Analysis, 1979-1983 (Box 89, Folder 7)
    (Primarily related to the City University of New York)
  - Articles on Music, 1962-1979, undated (Box 89, Folder 8)
  - Arizona, 1960-1980 (Box 89, Folder 9)
    (Primarily related to the University of Arizona)
  - Bellagio, 1982-1983 (Box 89, Folder 10)
    (Related to a residency, primarily to work on Frederick Douglass)
  - The Black Composer Speaks, 1974-1975 (Box 89, Folder 11)
    (Includes interview transcript)
  - Black Composers, 1974-1976, undated (Box 89, Folder 12)
  - Black Perspectives in Music, 1974-1982 (Box 89, Folder 13)
    (Includes lists of performances of Kay’s works, etc.)
  - Bleeker Street Memory, undated (Box 89, Folder 14)
    (Photocopies of two holographs. There is no clear relationship between this piece, whose composer is unidentified, and the Bleeker Street Suite.)
  - Books and Articles, 1950-1955, undated (Box 89, Folder 15)
    (Primarily by either Kay or George Rochberg)
  - Boulé (Zeta Boulé Dinner), 1985-1986 (Box 89, Folder 16)
  - Broadcast Music Inc. (BMI)
    - General, 1987-1994 (Box 89, Folder 17)
    - Autographs, 1975-1979 (Box 90, Folder 1)
      (Includes lists of works and catalog for brochure)
    - Clearance Forms, 1979-1984 (Box 90, Folder 2)
    - Contracts, 1941-1986 (2 Folders) (Box 90, Folder 3 to 4)
      (Includes list of titles, 1979)
    - Report, 1976-1983, 1993 (Box 90, Folder 5)
    - Student Composers Awards, 1987 (Box 90, Folder 6)
  - Broadcast Programs, 1972-1973 (Box 90, Folder 7)
  - Business Cards, undated (Box 90, Folder 8)
  - Capitoline Venus, 1971-1973 (2 Folders) (Box 90, Folder 9 to 10)
  - Carl Fischer, Inc.
    - General, 1974-1990 (2 Folders) (Box 90, Folder 11 to 12)
    - Carl Fischer/Cohn and Music Composers of America (MCA)-Belwin, 1969-1980 (Box 90, Folder 13)
    - Cohn, Arthur, 1976-1992 (2 Folders) (Box 90, Folder 14 to 15)
    - Contracts, 1974-1984 (Box 91, Folder 1)
    - Mailings, Receipt of Manuscripts, 1975-1984 (Box 91, Folder 2)
    - Manuscript Receipts, Publications, Statements, 1974-1976, 1985 (Box 91, Folder 3)
  - Catalogue, circa 1979 (Box 91, Folder 4)
    (Includes several typed lists)
  - C.F. Peters Corporation, 1976-1979 (Box 91, Folder 5)
  - Commissions, 1953-1973 (3 Folders) (Box 91, Folder 6 to 8)
  - Composition (Teaching Materials), undated (Box 91, Folder 9)
  - Contemporary Music, 1966-1968 (Box 91, Folder 10)
  - Contracts, 1949-1974, 1980-1988 (5 Folders) (Box 91, Folder 11 to 15)
  - Contracts and Royalty Statements, 1985-1996 (Box 92, Folder 1)
  - Copyist, 1966-1980 (Box 92, Folder 2)
  - Copyright, 1951-1979 (Box 92, Folder 3)
  - Cue Sheets, 1958-1964 (Box 92, Folder 4)
    (Includes list of Kay’s music that was used in television and film)
  - de Paur, Leonard
    - Correspondence, 1972 (Box 92, Folder 5)
    - Project, 1974-1975 (Box 92, Folder 6)
      (J.C. Penney Bicentennial)
  - Dickinson College, 1978 (Box 92, Folder 7)
    (Regarding honorary degree and residency)
  - Dorr, Donald, 1978-1991 (3 Folders) (Box 92, Folder 8 to 10)
    (The first file is primarily related to Frederick Douglass)
  - Duke University, 1988 (Box 92, Folder 11)
  - Eastman School of Music--Correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 92, Folder 12)
  - Engagements, 1967-1991 (3 Folders) (Box 92, Folder 13 to 15)
  - Epigrams and Hymn--Correspondence and Documents, 1974-1975 (Box 92, Folder 16)
  - Exhibits
    (of Kay’s materials)
    - 1979 (Box 92, Folder 17)
    - 1987 (Box 92, Folder 18)
  - FDR: From Third Term to Pearl Harbor--Commission and Contract, 1958 (Box 93, Folder 1)
  - Fellowship--Front Sheets, 1973-1986 (Box 93, Folder 2)
  - First Nocturne--Correspondence, 1973 (Box 93, Folder 3)
  - Foundations, 1968-1970 (Box 93, Folder 4)
  - Frederick Douglass
    - General, 1976-1991 (2 Folders) (Box 93, Folder 5 to 6)
    - Clippings, etc., 1985-1991 (Box 93, Folder 7)
      (Includes a list of Kay’s professional activities for 1978-1987)
    - Contract, 1991 (Box 93, Folder 8)
    - National Endowment for the Arts (NEA) Grant, 1978-1982 (Box 93, Folder 9)
  - Going Home--Correspondence, undated (Box 93, Folder 10)
  - Great Lakes Experience (Reunion), 1975-1976 (Box 93, Folder 11)
  - Guarantees, circa 1960-1965 (Box 93, Folder 12)
  - Guitar, 1989 (Box 93, Folder 13)
  - Harp & Guitar, undated (Box 93, Folder 14)
  - Holland, Michigan Chorale Society, 1981-1984 (Box 93, Folder 15)
  - Hotels, 1968-1983 (Box 93, Folder 16)
  - Jazz, 1990 (Box 93, Folder 17)
  - Jubilee
    - General, 1970-1989 (Box 93, Folder 18)
    - Clippings - Jubilee, 1976 (Box 93, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence, 1975, 1986 (2 Folders) (Box 93, Folder 20 to 21)
    - Delta Airlines Advertisement, 1976 (Box 103)
    - Reviews, 1976-1977 (Box 93, Folder 22)
  - Jubilee I--Opera/South, 1974-1976 (Box 93, Folder 23)
  - Jubilee II--Corrections, 1976-1977 (Box 93, Folder 24)
  - Juilliard School, 1974-1977 (Box 94, Folder 1)
  - Lancaster Symphony Orchestra, 1988-1989 (Box 94, Folder 2)
    (Composer’s Award)
  - Lecture, 1959-1967 (Box 94, Folder 3)
  - Lecture Outline, 1987 May 4 (Box 94, Folder 4)
  - Lehman College
    - General, 1968-1980, undated (Box 94, Folder 5)
    - Administration, 1969-1975, 1984 (Box 94, Folder 6)
    - Administration, Grant and Letters, 1975-1979 (Box 94, Folder 7)
    - Appointments, 1968-1972 (Box 94, Folder 8)
    - Faculty File on Kay, 1968-1987 (Box 94, Folder 9)
      (Includes clippings, press releases, and also materials related to Jubilee)
    - Memorial Invitation, 1995 (Box 94, Folder 10)
    - Syllabi MST 315 and 316 (Orchestration I and II), undated (Box 94, Folder 11)
    - Tribute Concert
      - Clippings, 1989 (Box 94, Folder 12)
      - Congratulatory Letters, 1989 (Box 94, Folder 13)
    - Vita, 1972-1982 (Box 94, Folder 14)
  - Library of Congress, 1961-1975 (Box 94, Folder 15)
    (Includes information on deposits, gifts, and commissions)
  - Libretti
    - Libretto, 1954-1968 (2 Folders) (Box 94, Folder 16 to 17)
      (The first Folder includes an inscribed copy of Langston Hughes’ libretto for "Soul Gone Home" (1954) )
    - Don Juan Tenorio and Soriee Musical, circa 1975 (Box 94, Folder 18)
    - Isadora (Outline) by Bernard Reines, undated (Box 94, Folder 19)
    - M.L. Originals, circa 1963 (Box 94)
      (Contains a libretto for The Game that includes annotations and corrections)
  - Lucky Strike Advertisement Featuring Kay, circa 1960 (Box 103)
  - Mailings, 1967-1968 (Box 94, Folder 20)
  - Meet the Composer, 1980-1983 (Box 94, Folder 21)
  - Mu Phi Epsilon, 1976-1978, 1990 (Box 95, Folder 1)
  - Music Composed for Kay on the Occasion of His Fiftieth Birthday, 1967 (Box 103)
  - Music Corporation of America (MCA)-Belwin, 1963-1982 (Box 95, Folder 2)
    (See Also: Box 90, Folder 13 Carl Fischer/Cohn and MCA-Belwin, 1969-1980)